geekymedics.com 2019-05-22

# Disclaimer and Privacy Policy | Geeky Medics

## 1\. Definitions and Interpretation

In this Policy the following terms shall have the following meanings:

“Account” means an account required to access and/or use certain areas and features of Our Site;

“Cookie” means a small text file placed on your computer or device by Our Site when you visit certain parts of Our Site and/or when you use certain features of Our Site. Details of the Cookies used by Our Site are set out in section 13, below;

“Cookie Law” means the relevant parts of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003;

“Personal data” means any and all data that relates to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified from that data. In this case, it means personal data that you give to Us via Our Site. This definition shall, where applicable, incorporate the definitions provided in the Data Protection Act 1998 and/or EU Regulation 2016/679 – the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”); and

“We/Us/Our” means Geeky Medics Limited, a company incorporated and registered in England and Wales with company number 09523980 whose registered office is at 47b Leazes Terrace, Newcastle Upon Tyne, Tyne and Wear NE1 4LZ.

* * *

## 2\. Information About Us

2.1 Our Site is owned and operated by Geeky Medics Limited of 47b Leazes Terrace, Newcastle Upon Tyne, Tyne and Wear NE1 4LZ.

2.2 You contact us by writing to us at the address above, or by emailing us at hey@geekymedics.com,

2.3 Our Data Protection Officer is Dr Lewis Potter.

* * *

## 3\. What Does This Policy Cover?

This Policy applies only to your use of Our Site. Our Site may contain links to other websites. Please note that We have no control over how your data is collected, stored, or used by other websites and We advise you to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing any data to them.

* * *

## 4\. Your Rights

4.1 As a data subject, you have the following rights under the GDPR, which this Policy and Our use of personal data have been designed to uphold:

4.1.1 The right to be informed about Our collection and use of personal data;

4.1.2 The right of access to the personal data We hold about you (see section 12);

4.1.3 The right to rectification if any personal data We hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete (please contact Us using the details in section 14);

4.1.4 The right to be forgotten – i.e. the right to ask Us to delete any personal data We hold about you (We only hold your personal data for a limited time, as explained in section 6 but if you would like Us to delete it sooner, please contact Us using the details in section 14);

4.1.5 The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data;

4.1.6 The right to data portability (obtaining a copy of your personal data to re-use with another service or organisation);

4.1.7 The right to object to Us using your personal data for particular purposes; and

4.1.8 Rights with respect to automated decision making and profiling.

4.2 If you have any cause for complaint about Our use of your personal data, please contact Us using the details provided in section 202 and We will do Our best to solve the problem for you. If We are unable to help, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the UK’s supervisory authority, the Information Commissioner’s Office.

4.3 For further information about your rights, please contact the Information Commissioner’s Office or your local Citizens Advice Bureau.

* * *

## 5\. What Data Do We Collect?

Depending upon your use of Our Site, We may collect some or all of the following personal and non-personal data (please also see section 13 on Our use of Cookies and similar technologies):

5.1 name;

5.2 Address;

5.3 Email address;

5.4 County of residence;

5.5 Educational background;

5.6 Educational performance;

5.7 IP address;

5.8 web browser type and version;

5.9 operating system.

* * *

## 6\. How Do We Use Your Data?

6.1 All personal data is processed and stored securely, for no longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. We will comply with Our obligations and safeguard your rights under the Data Protection Act 1998 or GDPR at all times. For more details on security see section 7, below.

6.2 Our use of your personal data will always have a lawful basis, either because it is necessary for Our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to Our use of your personal data (e.g. by subscribing to emails), or because it is in Our legitimate interests. Specifically, We may use your data for the following purposes:

6.2.1 Providing and managing your Account;

6.2.2 Providing and managing your access to Our Site;

6.2.3 Personalising and tailoring your experience on Our Site;

6.2.4 Supplying Our products and/or services to you (please note that We require your personal data in order to enter into a contract with you);

6.2.5 Personalising and tailoring Our products and/or services for you;

6.2.6 Replying to emails from you;

6.2.7 Supplying you with emails that you have opted into (you may unsubscribe or opt-out at any time clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our emails

6.2.8 Market research.

6.3 With your permission and/or where permitted by law, We may also use your data for marketing purposes which may include contacting you by email and/or telephone or text message or by post with information, news and offers on Our products and/or our services. We will not, however, send you any unsolicited marketing or spam and will take all reasonable steps to ensure that We fully protect your rights and comply with Our obligations under the Data Protection Act 1998 or GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.

6.4 You have the right to withdraw your consent to Us using your personal data at any time, and to request that We delete it.

6.5 We do not keep your personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. Data will therefore be retained for the following periods (or its retention will be determined on the following bases):

6.5.1 Data that could be used to personally identify you will be kept for as long as you have an active account registered with us to enable us to continue to provide you with our services.

* * *

## 7\. How and Where Do We Store Your Data?

7.1 We only keep your personal data for as long as We need to in order to use it as described above in section 6, and/or for as long as We have your permission to keep it.

7.2 Some or all of your data may be stored outside of the European Economic Area (“the EEA”) (The EEA consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein). If We do store data outside the EEA (this may be the case, for example, if Our email server is located in a country outside the EEA), We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated as safely and securely as it would be within the UK and under the Data Protection Act 1998 and/or GDPR.

7.3 Data security is very important to Us, and to protect your data We have taken suitable measures to safeguard and secure data collected through Our Site.

7.4 Steps We take to secure and protect your data include:

7.4.1 We store your data on a secure server managed by a GDPR compliant vendor.

7.4.2 Any data transferred to and from the server is encrypted during transfer.

7.4.3 Passwords are secured using the latest security algorithms and are not stored in plain text.

* * *

## 8\. Do We Share Your Data?

8.1 We may share anonymised aggregated data sets with third parties for research and marketing purposes.

8.2 Use of Intercom Services: We use third-party analytics services to help understand your usage of our services. In particular, we provide a limited amount of your information (such as sign-up date and some personal information like your email address and name) to Intercom, Inc. (“Intercom”) and utilize Intercom to collect data for analytics purposes when you visit our website or use our product. As a data processor acting on our behalf, Intercom analyzes your use of our website and/or product and tracks our relationship by way of cookies and similar technologies so that we can improve our service to you. For more information on Intercom's use of cookies, please visit https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#cookie-policy. We may also use Intercom as a medium for communications, either through email, or through messages within our product(s). For more information on the privacy practices of Intercom, please visit https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy. Intercom’s services are governed by Intercom’s terms of use which can be found at https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#terms. If you would like to opt out of having this information collected by or submitted to Intercom, please contact us.

8.3 We use Google Analytics to monitor and analyze web traffic and to keep track of User behavior. Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. Data is processed in the United States. Google's privacy policy can be viewed here: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en . You can opt out here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en .

8.4 In certain circumstances, We may be legally required to share certain data held by Us, which may include your personal data, for example, where We are involved in legal proceedings, where We are complying with legal obligations, a court order, or a governmental authority.

* * *

## 9\. What Happens If Our Business Changes Hands?

9.1 We may, from time to time, expand or reduce Our business and this may involve the sale and/or the transfer of control of all or part of Our business. Any personal data that you have provided will, where it is relevant to any part of Our business that is being transferred, be transferred along with that part and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this Privacy Policy, be permitted to use that data only for the same purposes for which it was originally collected by Us.

9.2 In the event that any of your data is to be transferred in such a manner, you will not be contacted in advance and informed of the changes.

* * *

## 10\. How Can You Control Your Data?

10.1 In addition to your rights under the GDPR, set out in section 4, when you submit personal data via Our Site, you may be given options to restrict Our use of your data. In particular, We aim to give you strong controls on Our use of your data for direct marketing purposes (including the ability to opt-out of receiving emails from Us which you may do by unsubscribing using the links provided in Our emails.

10.2 You may also wish to sign up to one or more of the preference services operating in the UK: The Telephone Preference Service (“the TPS”), the Corporate Telephone Preference Service (“the CTPS”), and the Mailing Preference Service (“the MPS”). These may help to prevent you receiving unsolicited marketing. Please note, however, that these services will not prevent you from receiving marketing communications that you have consented to receiving.

* * *

## 11\. Your Right to Withhold Information

11.1 You may access certain areas of Our Site without providing any data at all. However, to use all features and functions available on Our Site you may be required to submit or allow for the collection of certain data.

11.2 You may restrict Our use of Cookies. For more information, see section 13.

* * *

## 12\. How Can You Access Your Data?

You have the right to ask for a copy of any of your personal data held by Us (where such data is held). We will provide any and all information in response to your request free of charge. Please contact Us for more details at hey@geekymedics.com.

* * *

## 13\. Our Use of Cookies

13.1 Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

13.2 A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer’s hard drive.

We use the following cookies:

  * Strictly necessary cookies. These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services.
  * Analytical/performance cookies. They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
  * Functionality cookies. These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).
  * Targeting cookies. These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

13.3 Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

13.4 You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.

13.5 Except for essential cookies, all cookies will expire after 2 years.

* * *

## Changes To Our Policies

Any changes we make to our privacy or cookies policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

* * *

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us at hey@geekymedics.com.

* * *
